Isabella Karle and Jerome Karle Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Isabella Karle Papers, 1930-2010 (Box 1-173)
  - Research File, 1930-2008 (Box 55-173)
    - AC8CV7A, 2005, (3 folders) (Box 155)
    - AC8CV7A and ALAC7ALT, 2000-2005, (2 folders) (Box 155)
    - Acta Leah paper, figures and illustrations, 1990 (Box 155)
    - AIBOUT and AIBOUTC, 1993-2001 (Box 155)
    - Balaram, Padmanabhan, 1985-1987 (Box 155)
    - Balaram, Padmanabhan, 1987-1996, (6 folders) (Box 156)
    - Balaram, Padmanabhan, 1992-2004, (5 folders) (Box 157)
    - Balaram, Padmanabhan, 1997-2004, (2 folders) (Box 158)
    - BBH19LTA, 2002-2004 (Box 158)
    - BBH19LTA, 2003, mss85507_215_095
    - BBH19M, 2003-2007 (Box 158)
    - BBH19M, 2004-2005, mss85507_215_096; mss85507_215_097
    - BDPA1 and BDPA1LO, 2005 (Box 158)
    - BDPA1 and BDPA1LO, Crystallographic data, 2005, mss85507_215_098
    - BDPA12DR, 2005 (Box 158)
    - BDPA13 and BDP∝LP8, 2005-2006 (Box 158)
    - BH3 and BDPA12DR, 2008 (Box 158)
    - BISIM and TIMTFA, 1999-2007, mss85507_215_099
    - BISIM and TIMTFA, 2006-2007 (Box 158)
    - Channels research and reprints, 1968-1996 (Box 159)
    - Chronological file, 1930-1979, (4 folders) (Box 159)
    - Chronological file, 1980-1999, (5 folders) (Box 160)
    - Chronological file, circa 1992-2007, undated, (5 folders) (Box 161)
    - Chronological file, 1997-1999, mss85507_215_100; mss85507_215_101
    - Computer program manuals, 1962-1968 (Box 161)
    - Computer punched cards, undated (Box 162)
    - Corbin, J. D., x-ray film negatives, 1969 (Box 162)
    - C-penta, figures and illustrations, 1976-1977 (Box 162)
    - DFP16, 2005-2006 (Box 162)
    - Diffractograms, miscellany, circa 1970-circa 2000 See Container OV 63, same heading (Box OV 63)
    - DJ3, 2005, (2 folders) (Box 162)
    - DJ3, crystallographic data, 2005, mss85507_215_102; mss85507_215_103; mss85507_215_104
    - DP18CC and DP18C, 2005 (Box 162)
    - DPFM, 2006, mss85507_215_105
    - DPFM, 2006-2008, (2 folders) (Box 162)
    - DP5M, 2007 (Box 163)
    - DP5M and RANGA, 2007, (2 folders) (Box 163)
    - Figures and illustrations, miscellany, circa 1970-circa 2000 See also Container OV 63-OV 65, same heading (Box 163)
    - Frog venom research, 1967 (Box 163)
    - Future projects, 1988 See also Container OV 63, same heading (Box 163)
    - Geiger tubes, 1933-1956 (Box 163)
    - Gramicidin S, 1990 (Box 163)
    - Hydrogen bonding, 1974-1997 (Box 163)
    - ISARIAZ, 2004-2005 (Box 164)
    - ISPY and AC4, 1993-1998 (Box 164)
    - ISPY and AC4, 1997, mss85507_215_106
    - LDpg10, LDpg6, LDbg5, figures and illustrations, 1992-1994 (Box 164)
    - Lysozyme, 1937-1967, (3 folders) (Box 164)
    - Lysozyme, 1937-1967, (2 folders) (Box 165)
    - MAGAININ, 1989-1997 (Box 165)
    - MAPZ, 2008 (Box 165)
    - MAPZM, 2005-2008, (2 folders) (Box 165)
    - MAPZM, 2006, mss85507_215_107
    - Peptide and protein reprints and notes, 1966, 1974-1984 (Box 165)
    - Peptides research and reprints, 1972-1993 (Box 166)
    - Ranga4SI and RangaDP5M, 2001-2006, (2 folders) (Box 166)
    - Ranganathan, Darshan, 1993-1995, (2 folders) (Box 166)
    - Ranganathan, Darshan, 1995-1997, (7 folders) (Box 167)
    - Ranganathan, Darshan, 1998-2001, (5 folders) (Box 168)
    - Ranganathan, Darshan, 2000-2001, (3 folders) (Box 169)
    - Ranganathan, Subramania, 2003-2005 (Box 169)
    - RANGA01m and BISIM, 2005-2006 (Box 169)
    - RANGA01m and BISIM, Crystallographic data, figures, and illustrations, 2005-2006, mss85507_215_108; mss85507_215_109
    - RANGDP5M and RANG4S1, 2006, mss85507_215_110
    - RANGDP5M and RANG4S1, 2006-2007, (3 folders) (Box 169)
    - Research contracts and proposals, 1982-1987 (Box 170)
    - SHELX graphics instructions and examples, 1983-1989 (Box 170)
    - Si₂C1₆, 1938-1955, (3 folders) (Box 170)
    - TH1, 2002-2004 (Box 170)
    - TIMTFA, 2003-2005 (Box 171)
    - TIMTFA, 2004, mss85507_215_111
    - TIMTFA and BDPA12DR, 2006-2007 (Box 171)
    - TIMTFA and BISIM, 2005-2007, mss85507_215_112; mss85507_215_113
    - TIMTFA and BISIM, 2006-2007, (3 folders) (Box 171)
    - UL10 A,B,C, figures and illustrations, 1989 (Box 171)
    - Usubillaga steroid, x-ray film negatives, 1969 (Box 171)
    - U10DM, 1989 (Box 171)
    - U10ED, 1989 (Box 172)
    - U10TMP, 1990 (Box 172)
    - UU10IPR, UU10, and UA10, figures and illustrations, undated (Box 172)
    - Witkop, Bernhard (Box 172)
      - C₃₁H₃₈NO₆BR, frog venom negatives, 1967 (Box 172)
      - Photolysis, noncentro, 1966 (Box 172)
    - Witkop, Bernhard and J. D. Corbin
      - Crystallographic data printouts, 1968-1973 See Container OV 60-OV 61, same heading (Box OV 60-OV 61)
      - Figures and illustrations, circa 1966-circa 1979 See Container OV 61-OV 62, same heading (Box 172)
      - Frog venom crystallographic data printouts and illustrations, 1967 (Box OV 61-OV 62)
      - Miscellany, 1966-1972, (2 folders) (Box 173)
    - X-ray diffraction analyses of single crystals of small molecules and peptides (grant), 1985-1986, (2 folders) (Box 173)
- Jerome Karle Papers, 1912-2009 (Box 174-412)
  The Jerome Karle Papers document Karle’s contributions to the field of crystallography, his administrative career at NRL, and involvement in numerous scientific organizations, mostly between 1948 and 2008. The series features writings, speeches, correspondence, and subject files focusing on his research in structural chemistry, highlighting his work in crystal structure determination and the development of various diffraction techniques. It also comprises files pertaining to his roles in developing national and international science policy within the National Academy of Sciences, International Union of Crystallography, and American Academy of Crystallography.
  - Personal File, 1937-2009 (Box 174-179)
    The Personal File subseries contains materials that are primarily biographical and provide an overview of Jerome Karle’s life and career. Files include biographical sketches, awards, résumés, photographs, and clippings. The subseries documents Karle’s winning of the Nobel Prize in chemistry in 1985 (shared with Herbert A. Hauptman), including his subsequent involvement at various events as a Nobel laureate. Lectures presented at meetings of Nobel laureates in Lindau, Germany, are filed within the Speeches and Writings subseries. Additional biographical materials related to Karle can be found in the Collaborations series and include awards, clippings, and oral history interviews.
    Material types include résumés, awards, certificates, clippings, business cards, calendars, photographs, bibliographies, and correspondence.
    Arranged alphabetically by material type or subject.
    - Awards (Box 174)
      - Enrico Fermi Award, 1999 (Box 174)
      - Ettore Majorana Prize - Erice - Science for Peace (1992), 1994 (Box 174)
      - Miscellany, 1959-2008 (Box 174)
      - Nobel Prize (Box 174)
        - American Nobel Anniversary Committee, 1986-1987 (Box 174)
        - Clippings and media coverage, 1985-1986, (2 folders) (Box 174)
        - Correspondence, 1985-2004 (Box 174)
        - Electronic Nobel Museum, 1999-2000 See also Container 176, Nobel Foundation (Box 174)
        - Exhibits, 1999-2000 (Box 174)
        - "Facing the 21st Century: Threats and Promises," conference of Nobel laureates, Paris, France, 1988, Jan. 18-21 (Box 174)
        - "Facing the 21st Century: Threats and Promises," conference of Nobel laureates, Paris, France, 1988, Jan. 18-21, (3 folders) (Box 175)
        - Lecture, "Recovering Phase Information from Intensity Data," 1985 See also Container 214, Speeches, (2 folders) (Box 175)
        - Meetings of Nobel laureates in Lindau, Germany, 1992-2009 (Box 175)
        - Nobel Awards Dinner, Museum of Science and Industry, Chicago, Ill., 1986, Apr. 16 (Box 176)
        - Nobel Foundation, 1994-2001 See also Container 174, Electronic Nobel Museum (Box 176)
        - Nobel Foundation directory, 1987-1992 (Box 176)
        - "Nobel Hall of Science" exhibit, Museum of Science and Industry, Chicago, Ill., 1985-1986 (Box 176)
        - Nobel Jubilee (1991), 1990-1992, (2 folders) (Box 176)
        - "Special messages," 1985-1986 (Box 176)
      - Navy Distinguished Civilian Service Award, 1967-1968 (Box 176)
      - Nominations (Box 177)
        - Linus Pauling Award, 1982-1985 (Box 177)
        - Miscellany, 1959-1965, 1982-1983, 2001 (Box 177)
        - National Medal of Science, 1976-1986, 1998-1999 (Box 177)
      - University of Michigan, honorary doctorate, 1990 (Box 177)
    - Biographical sketches, 1958-2009, (3 folders) (Box 177)
    - Calendars, 1989-1995 (Box 177)
    - Calendars, 1996-1999 (Box 178)
    - Chair of Science for the Structure of Matter, Naval Research Laboratory, installation, 1968 (Box 178)
    - Clippings featuring Karle, 1963-2003 (Box 178)
    - Contacts, undated (Box 178)
    - Curricula vitae and résumés, circa 1950-circa 1999 For additional material see Container 284, Applications for employment (Box 178)
    - Identification cards, 1963, 1978-2006, undated (Box 178)
    - Photographs (Box 178)
      - Awards and honors, 1985-1986, undated (Box 178)
      - Karle in office, conference room, and lecture room, 1990 (Box 178)
      - Miscellany, group photographs, 1951, 1964-1967, 1993-1996 (Box 178)
      - Portraits, 1937, circa 1960s-circa 2000s (Box 179)
    - Publications citing Jerome Karle, 1974-1977, 2000-2003 (Box 179)
  - Correspondence, 1944-2009 (Box 179-197)
    The Correspondence subseries comprises professional correspondence received by Karle, the bulk of which spans from 1965 to 2000. Although some outgoing letters are included, the subseries largely consists of letters sent to Karle by colleagues, scientists, and admirers of his work, especially after he won the Nobel Prize. Topics include solicitation for comments on articles, vacancy announcements, arrangements for speaking engagements and conference appearances, reprint requests, and letters from individuals seeking his autograph or advice. Additional correspondence related to the Nobel Prize can be found in the Personal File. The bulk of the correspondence in this subseries is of a general nature. Letters and memoranda related to Karle’s career at NRL and within professional organizations are filed in relevant folders in the Organizations and Institutions subseries, and correspondence tied to specific projects or topics can be found within associated materials in the Subject File. Most letters addressed to both Isabella and Jerome can be found in the Collaborations series.
    Material types include letters, email printouts, memoranda, invitations, and greeting cards.
    - Chronological file, 1944-1955, (8 folders) (Box 179)
    - Chronological file, 1956-1963, (8 folders) (Box 180)
    - Chronological file, 1964-1967, (6 folders) (Box 181)
    - Chronological file, 1967-1969, (7 folders) (Box 182)
    - Chronological file, 1970-1972, (6 folders) (Box 183)
    - Chronological file, 1972-1974, (7 folders) (Box 184)
    - Chronological file, 1975-1977, (7 folders) (Box 185)
    - Chronological file, 1977-1980, (7 folders) (Box 186)
    - Chronological file, 1980-1982, (7 folders) (Box 187)
    - Chronological file, 1983-1984, (6 folders) (Box 188)
    - Chronological file, 1984-1986, (7 folders) (Box 189)
    - Chronological file, 1986-1988, (7 folders) (Box 190)
    - Chronological file, 1989-1992, (9 folders) (Box 191)
    - Chronological file, 1993-1996, (8 folders) (Box 192)
    - Chronological file, 1997-2001, (10 folders) (Box 193)
    - Chronological file, 2001-2009, undated, (12 folders) (Box 194)
    - Fan mail, 1985-2004, undated, (5 folders) (Box 195)
    - "Kind words," 1972-1993 (Box 195)
    - United States Congress, 1984-1994 (Box 195)
    - Reprint requests, 1951-1962, (2 folders) (Box 195)
    - Reprint requests, 1963-1977, (8 folders) (Box 196)
    - Reprint requests, 1978-1997, (8 folders) (Box 197)
  - Speeches and Writings, 1949-2008 (Box 197-222)
    The Speeches and Writings subseries comprises files related to articles, lectures, abstracts, reports, and a monograph written by Karle focusing on a range of topics relevant to his crystallography research. The bulk of the materials span from 1950 to 2000. In addition to published and unpublished writings, the files contain drafts, working files, correspondence, research, and other background material. Topics explored focus mostly on x-ray diffraction, gas electron diffraction, electron diffraction, anomalous dispersion, and quantum mechanics. Some writings focus on the analysis of crystal and molecular structure of specific compounds. Frequent collaborators represented in the subseries include Herbert A. Hauptman, Lou Massa, Lulu Huang, Richard Gilardi, John Konnert, Wayne Hendrickson, and Judith Flippen-Anderson. Speech files mostly include lectures presented at conferences, symposia, and workshops. Lectures related to classes taught by Karle at the University of Maryland can be found in the Organizations and Institutions subseries. Writings and speeches prepared in collaboration with Isabella Karle are within the Collaborations series.
    Material types include articles, abstracts, figures, illustrations, slides, correspondence, reports, presentations, testimonies, and speeches. Some textual and visual materials are in digital formats.
    Arranged alphabetically by material type and thereunder chronologically. The file structure of the digital content maintained as received.
    - Abstracts, 1978-1981, 2004, undated (Box 197)
    - Articles, 1949-1969, (8 folders) (Box 198)
    - Articles, 1971-1980, (10 folders) (Box 199)
    - Articles, 1980-1989, (10 folders) (Box 200)
    - Articles, 1988-1989, (8 folders) (Box 201)
    - Articles, 1989-1998, (10 folders) (Box 202)
    - Articles, 1995-1998, (9 folders) (Box 203)
    - Articles, 1998, (6 folders) (Box 204)
    - Articles, 1998-1999, (7 folders) (Box 205)
    - Articles, 1999, mss85507_215_008; mss85507_215_009
    - Articles, 1999-2001, (7 folders) (Box 206)
    - Articles, 2002-2003, (8 folders) (Box 207)
    - Articles, 2003-2005, (7 folders) (Box 208)
    - Articles, 2006-2008, undated, (4 folders) (Box 209)
    - Foreword, gas-phase electron issue of Structural Chemistry, 2000 (Box 209)
    - Foreword, Stereochemical Applications of Gas-Phase Electron Diffraction, 1986 (Box 209)
    - Monograph, Solution of the Phase Problem. I. The Centrosystemmetric Crystal by Karle and Herbert A. Hauptman, 1953, (3 folders) (Box 209)
    - "Report on Electron Diffraction Investigation of the Structure of Organic Films on Platinum, Iron, Aluminum and Copper," 1945 (Box 209)
    - Speeches, 1949-1959 (Box 209)
    - Speeches, 1960-1963, (7 folders) (Box 210)
    - Speeches, 1965-1979, (9 folders) (Box 211)
    - Speeches, 1974-1980, (12 folders) (Box 212)
    - Speeches, 1980-1983, (13 folders) (Box 213)
    - Speeches, 1985-1987 See also Container 174, Lecture, (13 folders) (Box 214)
    - Speeches, 1987-1988, (10 folders) (Box 215)
    - Speeches, 1989-1994, (9 folders) (Box 216)
    - Speeches, 1995-1996, (7 folders) (Box 217)
    - Speeches, 1996-1997, (5 folders) (Box 218)
    - Speeches, 1997-1999, (10 folders) (Box 219)
    - Speeches, 1999-2002, (9 folders) (Box 220)
    - Speeches, 2002, mss85507_215_010; mss85507_215_011
    - Speeches, 2002-2006, undated, (7 folders) (Box 221)
    - Speeches, 2006, mss85507_215_012
    - Speeches, undated See also Container OV 2, same heading, (2 folders) (Box 222)
    - Testimony before U.S. Congress, 1986, May 21 (Box 222)
  - Organizations and Institutions, 1941-2009 (Box 222-318)
    The Organizations and Institutions subseries documents Karle’s professional memberships, appointments, involvement in numerous crystallography organizations, and his career as an administrator at NRL, mostly from his appointment as chief scientist within the Laboratory for the Structure of Matter in 1968 through his retirement in 2009. The NRL materials include program reviews, progress reports, proposals, and performance evaluations. The subseries focuses mostly on Karle’s role as administrator at NRL, with research conducted under the auspices of the laboratory filed elsewhere throughout the series where appropriate. Karle held various leadership positions in many national and international crystallography organizations, most notably the International Union of Crystallographers, the American Crystallographic Association, and the United States of America Committee for Crystallography. The bulk of the files in this subseries details his roles within these organizations in the 1970s and 1980s. Karle was also active in general science organizations, most notably the National Academy of Sciences, the files of which focus mostly on his involvement on the Committee on Human Rights, 1991-1997, and as chair of the chemistry section, 1988-1991. Other notable organizations where he was involved on a wider level in affecting national science policy include the International Council of Scientific Unions, the National Research Council, and the National Science Foundation. The subseries also details his involvement on boards and committees at his various alma maters including City College of New York, the University of Michigan, and Abraham Lincoln High School in New York City. There are no files from his time as a student at these institutions. Files related to his involvement with the NATO Advanced Study Institute can be found in the Collaborations series.
    Material types include meeting minutes, agendas, notes, correspondence, proposals, conference programs, performance evaluations, itineraries, personnel actions, reports, newsletters, financial documents, ballots, press releases, and presentations. Some textual materials are in digital formats.
    Arranged alphabetically by name of organization or institution. The file structure of the digital content maintained as received.
    - Abraham Lincoln High School, New York, N.Y., 1985-2005 (Box 222)
    - American Academy of Achievement, 1992-2000 (Box 222)
    - American Chemical Society, 1946-1947, 1984, 1993-1998 (Box 222)
    - American Committee for the Weizmann Institute of Science, 1988-2001, 2008-2009, (2 folders) (Box 222)
    - American Crystallographic Association (Box 223)
      - Busing, William, correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 223)
      - Chronological file, 1944-1972, (6 folders) (Box 223)
      - Chronological file, 1972-1988, 2000-2005, (4 folders) (Box 224)
      - Fankuchan Award, 1973 (Box 224)
      - Finances, 1941-1949 (Box 224)
      - Job descriptions, 1973-1974 (Box 225)
      - Joint Committee on Powder Diffraction Standards, 1972 (Box 225)
      - Meetings and workshops, 1946-1948, 1959-1968, (3 folders) (Box 225)
      - Meetings and workshops, 1969-1974, (8 folders) (Box 226)
      - Meetings and workshops, 1974-1982, (10 folders) (Box 227)
      - Meetings and workshops, 1982-2001, (6 folders) (Box 228)
      - Meetings and workshops, 2005 (Box 229)
      - Membership directory, 1997 (Box 229)
      - Newsletters, 1957-1961, 1969-1986, (4 folders) (Box 229)
      - Newsletters, 1987-2002, (2 folders) (Box 230)
      - Presidential business, 1971-1972 (Box 230)
      - Stereo projector, 1971-1973 (Box 230)
      - United States of America Committee for Crystallography committee on intercongress meetings, 1971-1973 (Box 230)
      - Warren Award, 1972-1973 (Box 230)
    - American Institute of Physics, 1971-1973 (Box 230)
    - American Institute of Physics, 1972, 1980-1981, 1996-2007, (2 folders) (Box 231)
    - American Mathematical Society, 1979-1980, 2000-2003 (Box 231)
    - American Philosophical Society, 1990-1995, (6 folders) (Box 231)
    - American Philosophical Society, 1996-2005, (6 folders) (Box 232)
    - American Physical Society, 1948-2007 (Box 232)
    - American Physical Society, 1993-1999, (2 folders) (Box 233)
    - American Renaissance in Science Education (ARISE) Board of Advisors, 1995-1999 (Box 233)
    - Andrei Sakharov Institute, 1982-1986 (Box 233)
    - British Crystallographic Association, 1981-1991, (4 folders) (Box 233)
    - Chemical Heritage Foundation, 1989-2000 (Box 234)
    - ChildRight Worldwide, 1994-1995 (Box 234)
    - City University of New York, City College (Box 234)
      - Anniversary, 150 years, 1997 (Box 234)
      - Comprehensive Regional Center for Minorities, 1988-1989, (5 folders) (Box 234)
      - Fall academic convocation, 1979, Oct. 5 (Box 234)
      - Miscellany, 1986-2008 (Box 234)
      - Research Centers in Minority Institutions, 1989-1993, (3 folders) (Box 235)
    - Council for a Livable World Education Fund, 1990 (Box 235)
    - Crystallographic Society of America, 1950 (Box 235)
    - Ettore Majorana Foundation and Centre for Scientific Culture, 1988-2007, (2 folders) (Box 235)
    - Federation of American Scientists, 1986-2005, (2 folders) (Box 236)
    - Institute for Organic Compounds, 1954-1961 (Box 236)
    - International Centre for Scientific Culture, World Laboratory, 1989-1990 (Box 236)
    - International Council for Scientific Development, 1986-1993 (Box 236)
    - International Council for Scientific and Technical Information, 1984 (Box 236)
    - International Council of Scientific Unions See also Container 252, same heading; See also Container 275, Advisory Committee for the ICSU (Box 236)
      - Committee on Publications and Communications, 1982-1983, (2 folders) (Box 236)
      - Committee on Publications and Communications, 1984-1985 (Box 237)
      - Miscellany, 1978-1982 (Box 237)
      - Non discrimination statement, 1987-1988 (Box 237)
      - Publications, 1974, 1981-1985 (Box 237)
      - Symposium on Global Change, Ottawa, Canada, 1984, Sept. (Box 237)
    - International Society of Quantum Biology, 1982-2000 (Box 237)
    - International Union of Crystallography (Box 237)
      - Abrahams, S. C., 1982-1987, (2 folders) (Box 237)
      - Accounts, 1983-1984 (Box 238)
      - Acta Crystallographica, 1948-1991, (4 folders) (Box 238)
      - Acta Crystallographica subscriptions, 1981-1983 (Box 238)
      - Ad Hoc Committee on the Nomenclature of Disordered, Modulated and Polytypes Structures, 1981-1984 (Box 238)
      - Ad Hoc Committee on the Nomenclature of Symmetry, 1981-1984 (Box 238)
      - Board on International Organizations and Programs, questionnaire, 1978 See also Container 261, Board on International Organizations and Programs (Box 238)
      - Commission on Biological Macromolecular Crystallography, 1981-1987 (Box 238)
      - Commission on Charge, Spin, and Momentum of Density, 1982-1984 (Box 238)
      - Commission on Crystal Growth, 1981-1984 (Box 239)
      - Commission on Crystallographic Apparatus, 1978-1984 (Box 239)
      - Commission on Crystallographic Computing, 1970-1973, 1981-1984 (Box 239)
      - Commission on Crystallographic Data, 1981-1984 (Box 239)
      - Commission on Crystallographic Nomenclature, 1981-1983 (Box 239)
      - Commission on Crystallographic Studies at Controlled Pressures and Temperatures, 1981-1984 (Box 239)
      - Commission on Crystallographic Teaching, 1981-1984 (Box 239)
      - Commission on Electron Diffraction, 1981-1984 (Box 239)
      - Commission Evaluations, 1985-1987 (Box 239)
      - Commission on International Tables, 1980-1984 (Box 239)
      - Commission on International Tables, 1980-1984, (2 folders) (Box 240)
      - Commission on Journals, 1978-1986, (3 folders) (Box 240)
      - Commission on Neutron Diffraction, 1981-1988 (Box 241)
      - Commission on Structural Analysis of Organic and Biologically Active Small Molecules, 1982-1988 (Box 241)
      - Commission on Structure, reports, 1982-1984 (Box 241)
      - Commissions, miscellany, 1978-1988 (Box 241)
      - Committee on Contents of Futures International Tables, 1972, 1979-1981, (2 folders) (Box 241)